Guide to the William Grabowski Photographs 1980s, 2004-2022 PR 321
New-York Historical Society
- Series III: Brooklyn, 2005, 2015-2020
  - Art. Graffiti / Street Art / Murals (58) (4 folders), 2015-2016 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10-13)
    All images are from Bushwick, except for two from Williamsburg, which includes one from Annoyance Theater. The Bushwick images include a few of the street artists creating the work.
  - Art. Graffiti / Street Art / Murals (5), 2017 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 4)
  - Art. Graffiti / Street Art / Murals. Bushwick Collective (31), 2017 May(?) (Offsite-box 4, Folder 5)
  - Art. Graffiti / Street Art / Murals. Bushwick Collective (20), 2017 December (Offsite-box 4, Folder 6)
  - Art. Graffiti / Street Art / Murals. Bushwick Collective (33), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Art. Graffiti / Street Art / Murals. Bushwick Collective (16), 2020 (Offsite-box 8)
  - Art. Graffiti / Street Art / Murals. Williamsburg (13), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 3)
  - Barclay's Center (2), 2020 (Offsite-box 8)
    1 photo of exterior, 1 photo of mural memorial of Kobe Bryant and daughter Gianna.
  - Domino Park (11), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 4)
    Includes signage, park features along East River waterfront, building tower, and street art/graffiti on construction site barrier walls.
  - Dyker Heights Holiday Decorations and Lights (13), 2017 December (Offsite-box 4, Folder 7A)
    Photographs co-created by Holly Grabowski.
  - Dyker Heights Holiday Decorations and Lights (8), 2020 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 7B)
  - Museums (2), 2016 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    Brooklyn Museum (exterior), Transit Museum (interior exhibit)
  - Parks and Gardens (9), 2016 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 15)
    Coney Island (rides, Nathan's signage, Scream Zone entrance), Botanic Garden, Jane's Carousel in Brooklyn Bridge Park.
  - Parks. Brooklyn Botanic Garden (10), 2017 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 8)
    Some of the photographs include views of the park's cherry blossoms.
  - Parks. Brooklyn Botanic Garden (8), 2019 May (Offsite-box 7, Folder 5)
    Includes springtime views of cherry blossoms, conservatory interior and exterior, and other buildings
  - Schools and Colleges (3), 2015 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
    Brooklyn College (Roosevelt Hall, West Quad, Library).
  - Schools and Colleges (18), 2017 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9)
    3 photographs of Brooklyn College (Library exterior, Quad, Gi60 stage), June. 15 photos of Pratt Institute (most are of outdoor sculptures; also Terian Design Center, main gate, main building, Memorial Hall), December.
  - Soldiers & Sailors Memorial Arch (1), 2020 (Offsite-box 8)
  - Street Views (4), 2005-2017 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 17)
    Line of customers at Rainbow Bagel Store; Park Slope townhouse; Williamsburg Bridge and parallel street with large scale street art/mural on building; homeless man with possessions in shopping carts (2017).
  - Various (3), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 5)
    Includes: skyline view of Coney Island from within Brooklyn, including Parachute Jump skeleton; Lady of Czestochowa church; and Green-Wood Cemetery entrance arch.
- Series IV: Queens, 2010, 2013-2021
  The series holds 205 photographs taken in the New York City borough of Queens. 72 of the photographs are of street art/murals. Among these are 42 images that document the murals at the 5 Pointz complex in Long Island City, their eventual destruction, and the new construction at the site (2013-2016). Another 18 images are of murals in Astoria, especially Welling Court (2017).
  18 images date from April 2020 and were taken at the height of the Covid-19 pandemic's impact on New York City; these images include shuttered storefronts, ambulances, signage, Elmhurst Hospital trauma center tents, and people wearing masks.
  Other photographs in this series include street vendors/festivals, Fort Totten, the Pepsi Cola sign on the East River in Gantry Plaza State Park, scenes from Flushing Meadow Park, JFK Airport, Alley Pond Park, and others. The container list provides a more detailed summary for each folder.
  - Airports (2), 2015 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
    JFK Airport (tarmac, TWA terminal)
  - Airports (13), 2017 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 5)
    One photo of the roadway approaching LaGuardia Airport. The other photos are of John F. Kennedy (JFK) Airport (interiors, exteriors, tarmac, TWA Terminal, AirTrain).
  - Airports (10), 2018 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 2)
    All of John F. Kennedy (JFK) Airport: views of the tarmac and runways with planes (e.g. Virgin Atlantic, JetBlue, Singapore Airlines), Aer Lingus jet taking off, AirTrain, roadways (passenger drop-off area, exit signage), Terminal 15 interior, TWA Terminal.
  - Airports (8), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 7)
    Includes John F. Kennedy (JFK) (5): planes on tarmac, interior of international terminal 1, artwork, roadways; LaGuardia (2) control tower and roadways; Grand Central Parkway airport exit.
  - Art. 5 Pointz, Long Island City (42) (3 folders), 2013-2016 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2-4)
    Folder 11.1 holds 14 images from July 2013 of the street art/graffiti/murals at 5 Pointz, prior to their destruction. Folder 11.2 holds 17 images from January and June 2014 of the defaced/painted over artwork. Folder 11.3 holds 5 images of the destroyed building (January 2015), two images of artwork from November 2015, and four images of new construction (2016).
  - Art. Astoria / Welling Court (18), 2017 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 6)
    11 photographs of street art (10 of which are murals) at Welling Court, Astoria, November 2017. 7 photos of street art/murals from unspecified locations in Astoria.
  - Art, Street (3), 2018 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 4)
    Two details (including description label) from the 63rd Drive Underpass Art Installation and one of a mural featuring cartoon characters (e.g., Bart and Homer Simpson, Pokemon Pikachu).
  - Art, Street (2), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
  - Art, Street. 88th Road Tunnel, Bellerose (7), 2021 (Offsite-box 8)
  - Citifield (New York Mets home field) / Sports Stadium (2), 2015, 2017 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
    Two exteriors, day (2015) and night (2017.
  - Citifield (3), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
    2 photos depict the WorldsFARE event of May on the grounds, one with the stadium in the background, one a close-up of a vendor's merchandise; 1 photo of the stadium
  - Covid-19 Pandemic (18), 2020 (Offsite-box 8)
  - Museum (4), 2013-2015 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
    Queens Museum, Queens Theatre, MoMA PS 1 outdoor sculpture
  - Museum (1), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
    Queens Museum exterior
  - Parks and Gardens (13), 2015-2016 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
    Flushing Meadow Park (Flame Thrower, Meadow Lake, New York State Pavilion and Towers, Unisphere, 1939-40 mosaic), Gantry Park (Pepsi sign), Manhattan skyline from Hunter's Point South Park.
  - Parks and Cemeteries (14), 2017 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 7)
    5 photographs of Cunningham Park during a performance of the New York Philharmonic and fireworks (June). 7 photographs of Fort Totten, including Bayside Historical Society. 2 photographs of cemeteries: Mount Olivet and Mount Hope (the photo of Mount Hope was co-created by Holly Grabowski).
  - Parks (2), 2018 June (Offsite-box 6, Folder 4)
    New York Philharmonic on stage and fireworks, both in Cunningham Park.
  - Parks and Cemeteries (4), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
    Includes Alley Pond Park (2) and Calvary Cemetery (2), looking out over headstones and with Manhattan skyline in distance.
  - Rego Park Street Festival (9), 2018 May (Offsite-box 6, Folder 3)
    Street vendors (8) and children's bounce houses (1).
  - Schools and Colleges (3), 2016-2017 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    Queens College (Quad, Kupferberg Center signage, Lefrak Concert Hall interior during concert performance)
  - Schools and Colleges (2), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
    Queens College Reeves Avenue entrance and musical performance at Lefrak Concert Hall
  - Street Views (5), 2010, 2016 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
    Street vendor on Queens Boulevard, Rego Park (2010); Street fair vendors (2016)
  - Street Views (11), 2017 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 8)
    63rd Drive Street Fair in Rego Park (3 images including one of the entrance to the subway); Steinway Street Festival in Astoria (6 images); End Alzheimer's Walk in Little Bay Park (1 image); panhandler (1 image).
  - Various (5), 2017 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 9)
    4 photographs of billboards and other advertising along the Long Island Expressway (LIE) (some for the musical "Hamilton," one with an obstructed view of the Manhattan skyline especially the Citicorp building). 1 photo from across the East River of the landmark Pepsi Cola sign, in Gantry Plaza State Park, with buildings rising above.
  - Various (2), 2018 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 4)
    Exteriors of Queens Atrium Corporate Center and Blanchard Building.
  - Various (2), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
    Includes Skyline Tower under construction (next to Citi Tower) and Jackson Park tower.
- Series V. Staten Island, 2017
  The series holds 13 photographs taken in November 2017: 8 photos of street art/murals, and one each of Staten Island Zoo carousel; Snug Harbor Cultural Center (signage/partial exterior); Snug Harbor Artist Residency Program building; Borough Hall; and North Shore esplanade with view of lower Manhattan skyline.
  All held in one folder.
  - Staten Island (13), 2017 November (Offsite-box 5, Folder 10)
- Series VI. Bridges, Tunnels, Ferries, 2015-2020
  The series holds 57 photographs of bridges (mostly) and tunnels connecting New York City's boroughs or connecting the city to locations outside it. The photographs include both images of the bridges taken from a distance that take in large portions of it and also close-ups of towers, cables, roadway traffic, pedestrians, and the like. Some images include skylines or other views in the distance.
  The series is arranged by subject, then chronologically. The number of photographs in each folder is noted in parentheses in the container list.
  - Bridges (11), 2015-2016 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 1)
    Rush Hour on George Washington Bridge; Brooklyn Bridge: walkway and from below (Manhattan skyline in background), vendors, cables, view of Statue of Liberty; Manhattan Bridge, framing Empire State Building; Ed Koch Bridge (Queensboro Bridge); Throgs Neck; Kosciuszko.
  - Bridges (19), 2017-2018 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 2)
    2017: Robert F. Kennedy Bridge (Triborough Bridge); old Kosciuszko Bridge (with new in background); new Kosciusko Bridge (one at day, one at night); Manhattan Bridge (arch and colonnade at entrance, roadway); Throgs Neck Bridge; George Washington Bridge; Macombs Dam Bridge; Ed Koch Bridge (Queensboro Bridge), 3 images, including one within Queens with MoMA's PS1 in foreground; Park Avenue Railroad Bridge; Roosevelt Island Bridge; Roosevelt Island Tramway base; Verrazano Narrows Bridge. 2018: Throgs Neck Bridge (1)
  - Bridges (15), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 6)
    Includes: Harlem River Span (1); Hell Gate (1); Kosciuszko (2); Edward Koch (1); Robert F. Kennedy (1); Goethals (1); Willis Avenue (1); Robert F. Kennedy and Hell Gate (1); Wards Island footbridge (1); High Bridge (3), one with Highbridge water tower (1); Macombs Dam (2).
  - Bridges (2), 2020 (Offsite-box 8)
    Includes Brooklyn Bridge (1) and Williamsburg Bridge (1)
  - Tunnels (5), 2012-2017 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 3)
    Midtown Tunnel (toll booth, interior traffic and lanes in infrared color, interior during 2017 reconstruction); Holland Tunnel (interior).
  - Tunnels (2), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 6)
    Includes Midtown Tunnel interior and exit in Manhattan.
  - Tunnels (1), 2020 (Offsite-box 8)
    Includes entrance to Hugh Carey Tunnel(Brooklyn–Battery Tunnel).
  - Ferries (2), 2019 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 6)
    Includes ferry from Battery Park to Statue of Liberty (Miss Ellis Island) and a New York Water Taxi.
- Series VII. Statue of Liberty & Ellis Island, 2016-2019
  - Statue of Liberty & Ellis Island (18), 2016-2020 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 16)
    Views of Statue from a distance across the water (3). Interior of Statue of Liberty, looking up spiral staircase (2). Exterior of Statue from various close angles (3). Museum and exhibits (4). Ellis Island buildings exterior and interior (6).